[
    {
        "question": "Who is the hero of this story?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the full titles of the Maharaja of Pratibandapuram?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is his name often shortened to?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the author's stated intention in telling the story?",
        "answer": "I have come forward to tell you why he came to be known as Tiger King. I have no intention of pretending to advance only to end in a strategic withdrawal. Even the threat of a Stuka bomber will not throw me off track. The Stuka, if it likes, can beat a hasty retreat from my story.",
        "extract": "I have come forward to tell you why he came to be known as Tiger King. I have no intention of pretending to advance only to end in a strategic withdrawal. Even the threat of a Stuka bomber will not throw me off track. The Stuka, if it likes, can beat a hasty retreat from my story.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L3:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will not throw the author off track?",
        "answer": "I have come forward to tell you why he came to be known as Tiger King. I have no intention of pretending to advance only to end in a strategic withdrawal. Even the threat of a Stuka bomber will not throw me off track. The Stuka, if it likes, can beat a hasty retreat from my story.",
        "extract": "I have come forward to tell you why he came to be known as Tiger King. I have no intention of pretending to advance only to end in a strategic withdrawal. Even the threat of a Stuka bomber will not throw me off track. The Stuka, if it likes, can beat a hasty retreat from my story.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L3:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the matter of vital importance that the author discloses at the start?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the natural desire of everyone who reads of the Tiger King?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is there any chance of this desire being fulfilled?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What has the Tiger King reached?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "In other words, what is the state of the Tiger King?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a matter of extraordinary interest?",
        "answer": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "extract": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L7:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "When can the manner of his death be revealed?",
        "answer": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "extract": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L7:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the most fantastic aspect of his demise?",
        "answer": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "extract": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L7:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What had astrologers foretold as soon as he was born?",
        "answer": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "extract": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L7:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the prediction for the child's future?",
        "answer": "But everyone in the kingdom remembered the astrologer\u2019s prediction. Many continued to discuss the matter. Slowly it came to the Maharaja\u2019s ears.",
        "extract": "But everyone in the kingdom remembered the astrologer\u2019s prediction. Many continued to discuss the matter. Slowly it came to the Maharaja\u2019s ears.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L37:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the astrologers do when they had to continue their prediction?",
        "answer": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "extract": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L9:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the astrologers say was a secret that should not be revealed?",
        "answer": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "extract": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L9:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will the child born under this star have to do one day?",
        "answer": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "extract": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L9:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened at that very moment?",
        "answer": "At that very moment a great miracle took place. An astonishing phrase emerged from the lips of the ten-day-old Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, \u201cO wise prophets!\u201d",
        "extract": "At that very moment a great miracle took place. An astonishing phrase emerged from the lips of the ten-day-old Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, \u201cO wise prophets!\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L11:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What phrase emerged from the lips of the ten-day-old Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur?",
        "answer": "At that very moment a great miracle took place. An astonishing phrase emerged from the lips of the ten-day-old Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, \u201cO wise prophets!\u201d",
        "extract": "At that very moment a great miracle took place. An astonishing phrase emerged from the lips of the ten-day-old Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, \u201cO wise prophets!\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L11:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did everyone react?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the infant say next?",
        "answer": "This time there were no grounds for doubt. It was the infant born just ten days ago who had enunciated the words so clearly.",
        "extract": "This time there were no grounds for doubt. It was the infant born just ten days ago who had enunciated the words so clearly.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L17:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How old was the infant who enunciated the words so clearly?",
        "answer": "This time there were no grounds for doubt. It was the infant born just ten days ago who had enunciated the words so clearly.",
        "extract": "This time there were no grounds for doubt. It was the infant born just ten days ago who had enunciated the words so clearly.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L17:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the chief astrologer do?",
        "answer": "The chief astrologer took off his spectacles and gazed intently at the baby.",
        "extract": "The chief astrologer took off his spectacles and gazed intently at the baby.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L19:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the royal infant say about the prediction of his death?",
        "answer": "\u201cAll those who are born will one day have to die. We don\u2019t need your predictions to know that. There would be some sense in it if you could tell us the manner of that death,\u201d the royal infant uttered these words in his little squeaky voice.",
        "extract": "\u201cAll those who are born will one day have to die. We don\u2019t need your predictions to know that. There would be some sense in it if you could tell us the manner of that death,\u201d the royal infant uttered these words in his little squeaky voice.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L21:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the chief astrologer do in wonder?",
        "answer": "The chief astrologer placed his finger on his nose in wonder. A baby barely ten days old opens its lips in speech! Not only that, it also raises intelligent questions! Incredible! Rather like the bulletins issued by the war office, than facts.",
        "extract": "The chief astrologer placed his finger on his nose in wonder. A baby barely ten days old opens its lips in speech! Not only that, it also raises intelligent questions! Incredible! Rather like the bulletins issued by the war office, than facts.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L23:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the chief astrologer say about the prince's birth?",
        "answer": "The chief astrologer took his finger off his nose and fixed his eyes upon the little prince.",
        "extract": "The chief astrologer took his finger off his nose and fixed his eyes upon the little prince.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L25:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship between the Bull and the Tiger?",
        "answer": "\u201cThe prince was born in the hour of the Bull. The Bull and the Tiger are enemies, therefore, death comes from the Tiger,\u201d he explained.",
        "extract": "\u201cThe prince was born in the hour of the Bull. The Bull and the Tiger are enemies, therefore, death comes from the Tiger,\u201d he explained.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L27:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore, where does death come from?",
        "answer": "\u201cThe prince was born in the hour of the Bull. The Bull and the Tiger are enemies, therefore, death comes from the Tiger,\u201d he explained.",
        "extract": "\u201cThe prince was born in the hour of the Bull. The Bull and the Tiger are enemies, therefore, death comes from the Tiger,\u201d he explained.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L27:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the crown prince's reaction to hearing the word 'Tiger'?",
        "answer": "You may think that crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur was thrown into a quake when he heard the word \u2018Tiger\u2019. That was exactly what did not happen. As soon as he heard it pronounced, the crown prince gave a deep growl. Terrifying words emerged from his lips.",
        "extract": "You may think that crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur was thrown into a quake when he heard the word \u2018Tiger\u2019. That was exactly what did not happen. As soon as he heard it pronounced, the crown prince gave a deep growl. Terrifying words emerged from his lips.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L29:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the crown prince say?",
        "answer": "You may think that crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur was thrown into a quake when he heard the word \u2018Tiger\u2019. That was exactly what did not happen. As soon as he heard it pronounced, the crown prince gave a deep growl. Terrifying words emerged from his lips.",
        "extract": "You may think that crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur was thrown into a quake when he heard the word \u2018Tiger\u2019. That was exactly what did not happen. As soon as he heard it pronounced, the crown prince gave a deep growl. Terrifying words emerged from his lips.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L29:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nature of this account?",
        "answer": "This account is only a rumour rife in Pratibandapuram. But with hindsight we may conclude it was based on some truth.",
        "extract": "This account is only a rumour rife in Pratibandapuram. But with hindsight we may conclude it was based on some truth.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L33:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grow up?",
        "answer": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "extract": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L35:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was his childhood like?",
        "answer": "The chief astrologer placed his finger on his nose in wonder. A baby barely ten days old opens its lips in speech! Not only that, it also raises intelligent questions! Incredible! Rather like the bulletins issued by the war office, than facts.",
        "extract": "The chief astrologer placed his finger on his nose in wonder. A baby barely ten days old opens its lips in speech! Not only that, it also raises intelligent questions! Incredible! Rather like the bulletins issued by the war office, than facts.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L23:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what age did he come of age?",
        "answer": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "extract": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L35:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened when he came of age?",
        "answer": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "extract": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L35:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did everyone in the kingdom remember?",
        "answer": "But everyone in the kingdom remembered the astrologer\u2019s prediction. Many continued to discuss the matter. Slowly it came to the Maharaja\u2019s ears.",
        "extract": "But everyone in the kingdom remembered the astrologer\u2019s prediction. Many continued to discuss the matter. Slowly it came to the Maharaja\u2019s ears.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L37:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja start out on?",
        "answer": "There were innumerable forests in the Pratibandapuram State. They had tigers in them. The Maharaja knew the old saying, \u2018You may kill even a cow in self-defence\u2019. There could certainly be no objection to killing tigers in self-defence. The Maharaja started out on a tiger hunt.",
        "extract": "There were innumerable forests in the Pratibandapuram State. They had tigers in them. The Maharaja knew the old saying, \u2018You may kill even a cow in self-defence\u2019. There could certainly be no objection to killing tigers in self-defence. The Maharaja started out on a tiger hunt.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L39:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Maharaja's reaction to killing his first tiger?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja was thrilled beyond measure when he killed his first tiger. He sent for the State astrologer and showed him the dead beast.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja was thrilled beyond measure when he killed his first tiger. He sent for the State astrologer and showed him the dead beast.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L41:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did he do with the dead beast?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja was thrilled beyond measure when he killed his first tiger. He sent for the State astrologer and showed him the dead beast.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja was thrilled beyond measure when he killed his first tiger. He sent for the State astrologer and showed him the dead beast.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L41:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the State astrologer say when the Maharaja showed him the first dead tiger?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja was thrilled beyond measure when he killed his first tiger. He sent for the State astrologer and showed him the dead beast.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja was thrilled beyond measure when he killed his first tiger. He sent for the State astrologer and showed him the dead beast.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L41:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the astrologer warn the Maharaja to be careful with?",
        "answer": "But he had to be extremely careful with that last tiger. What had the late chief astrologer said? \u201cEven after killing ninety-nine tigers the Maharaja should beware of the hundredth...\u2019\u2019 True enough. The tiger was a savage beast after all. One had to be wary of it. But where was that hundredth tiger to be found? It seemed easier to find tiger\u2019s milk than a live tiger.",
        "extract": "But he had to be extremely careful with that last tiger. What had the late chief astrologer said? \u201cEven after killing ninety-nine tigers the Maharaja should beware of the hundredth...\u2019\u2019 True enough. The tiger was a savage beast after all. One had to be wary of it. But where was that hundredth tiger to be found? It seemed easier to find tiger\u2019s milk than a live tiger.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L109:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What would the astrologer do if the hundredth tiger were also killed?",
        "answer": "\u201cWhat if the hundredth tiger were also killed?\u201d",
        "extract": "\u201cWhat if the hundredth tiger were also killed?\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L51:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "From that day onwards, what was it time for in Pratibandapuram?",
        "answer": "From that day onwards it was celebration time for all the tigers inhabiting Pratibandapuram.",
        "extract": "From that day onwards it was celebration time for all the tigers inhabiting Pratibandapuram.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L59:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the State ban?",
        "answer": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "extract": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L35:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What proclamation was issued?",
        "answer": "The State banned tiger hunting by anyone except the Maharaja. A proclamation was issued to the effect that if anyone dared to fling so much as a stone at a tiger, all his wealth and property would be confiscated.",
        "extract": "The State banned tiger hunting by anyone except the Maharaja. A proclamation was issued to the effect that if anyone dared to fling so much as a stone at a tiger, all his wealth and property would be confiscated.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L61:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja vow?",
        "answer": "\u201cI have killed the hundredth tiger. My vow has been fulfilled,\u201d the Maharaja was overcome with elation. Ordering the tiger to be brought to the capital in grand procession, the Maharaja hastened away in his car.",
        "extract": "\u201cI have killed the hundredth tiger. My vow has been fulfilled,\u201d the Maharaja was overcome with elation. Ordering the tiger to be brought to the capital in grand procession, the Maharaja hastened away in his car.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L131:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What dangers did the Maharaja face?",
        "answer": "Not that he faced no dangers. There were times when the bullet missed its mark, the tiger leapt upon him and he fought the beast with his bare hands. Each time it was the Maharaja who won.",
        "extract": "Not that he faced no dangers. There were times when the bullet missed its mark, the tiger leapt upon him and he fought the beast with his bare hands. Each time it was the Maharaja who won.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L65:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened at another time?",
        "answer": "At another time he was in danger of losing his throne. A high-ranking British officer visited Pratibandapuram. He was very fond of hunting tigers. And fonder of being photographed with the tigers he had shot. As usual, he wished to hunt tigers in Pratibandapuram. But the Maharaja was firm in his resolve. He refused permission.",
        "extract": "At another time he was in danger of losing his throne. A high-ranking British officer visited Pratibandapuram. He was very fond of hunting tigers. And fonder of being photographed with the tigers he had shot. As usual, he wished to hunt tigers in Pratibandapuram. But the Maharaja was firm in his resolve. He refused permission.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L67:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the high-ranking British officer fond of?",
        "answer": "At another time he was in danger of losing his throne. A high-ranking British officer visited Pratibandapuram. He was very fond of hunting tigers. And fonder of being photographed with the tigers he had shot. As usual, he wished to hunt tigers in Pratibandapuram. But the Maharaja was firm in his resolve. He refused permission.",
        "extract": "At another time he was in danger of losing his throne. A high-ranking British officer visited Pratibandapuram. He was very fond of hunting tigers. And fonder of being photographed with the tigers he had shot. As usual, he wished to hunt tigers in Pratibandapuram. But the Maharaja was firm in his resolve. He refused permission.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L67:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did he wish to do in Pratibandapuram?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Maharaja's response?",
        "answer": "But everyone in the kingdom remembered the astrologer\u2019s prediction. Many continued to discuss the matter. Slowly it came to the Maharaja\u2019s ears.",
        "extract": "But everyone in the kingdom remembered the astrologer\u2019s prediction. Many continued to discuss the matter. Slowly it came to the Maharaja\u2019s ears.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L37:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the British officer's secretary send word to the Maharaja about?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was important to the durai?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did the Maharaja not agree to this proposal?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the result of the Maharaja preventing the British officer from fulfilling his desire?",
        "answer": "Because he prevented a British officer from fulfilling his desire, the Maharaja stood in danger of losing his kingdom itself.",
        "extract": "Because he prevented a British officer from fulfilling his desire, the Maharaja stood in danger of losing his kingdom itself.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L73:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja and the dewan do?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the result of their deliberations?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja and the dewan held deliberations over this issue. As a result, a telegram was despatched forthwith to a famous British company of jewellers in Calcutta. \u2018Send samples of expensive diamond rings of different designs.\u2019",
        "extract": "The Maharaja and the dewan held deliberations over this issue. As a result, a telegram was despatched forthwith to a famous British company of jewellers in Calcutta. \u2018Send samples of expensive diamond rings of different designs.\u2019",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L75:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many rings arrived?",
        "answer": "Some fifty rings arrived. The Maharaja sent the whole lot to the British officer\u2019s good lady. The king and the minister expected the duraisani to choose one or two rings and send the rest back. Within no time at all the duraisani sent her reply: \u2018Thank you very much for your gifts.\u2019",
        "extract": "Some fifty rings arrived. The Maharaja sent the whole lot to the British officer\u2019s good lady. The king and the minister expected the duraisani to choose one or two rings and send the rest back. Within no time at all the duraisani sent her reply: \u2018Thank you very much for your gifts.\u2019",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L77:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja do with the rings?",
        "answer": "On the following day, the same old tiger wandered into the Maharaja\u2019s presence and stood as if in humble supplication, \u201cMaster, what do you command of me?\u2019\u2019 It was with boundless joy that the Maharaja took careful aim at the beast. The tiger fell in a crumpled heap.",
        "extract": "On the following day, the same old tiger wandered into the Maharaja\u2019s presence and stood as if in humble supplication, \u201cMaster, what do you command of me?\u2019\u2019 It was with boundless joy that the Maharaja took careful aim at the beast. The tiger fell in a crumpled heap.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L129:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the king and the minister expect the duraisani to do?",
        "answer": "Some fifty rings arrived. The Maharaja sent the whole lot to the British officer\u2019s good lady. The king and the minister expected the duraisani to choose one or two rings and send the rest back. Within no time at all the duraisani sent her reply: \u2018Thank you very much for your gifts.\u2019",
        "extract": "Some fifty rings arrived. The Maharaja sent the whole lot to the British officer\u2019s good lady. The king and the minister expected the duraisani to choose one or two rings and send the rest back. Within no time at all the duraisani sent her reply: \u2018Thank you very much for your gifts.\u2019",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L77:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the duraisani's reply?",
        "answer": "Some fifty rings arrived. The Maharaja sent the whole lot to the British officer\u2019s good lady. The king and the minister expected the duraisani to choose one or two rings and send the rest back. Within no time at all the duraisani sent her reply: \u2018Thank you very much for your gifts.\u2019",
        "extract": "Some fifty rings arrived. The Maharaja sent the whole lot to the British officer\u2019s good lady. The king and the minister expected the duraisani to choose one or two rings and send the rest back. Within no time at all the duraisani sent her reply: \u2018Thank you very much for your gifts.\u2019",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L77:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much was the bill from the British jewellers?",
        "answer": "In two days a bill for three lakh of rupees came from the British jewellers. The Maharaja was happy that though he had lost three lakh of rupees, he had managed to retain his kingdom.",
        "extract": "In two days a bill for three lakh of rupees came from the British jewellers. The Maharaja was happy that though he had lost three lakh of rupees, he had managed to retain his kingdom.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L79:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Maharaja happy about?",
        "answer": "In two days a bill for three lakh of rupees came from the British jewellers. The Maharaja was happy that though he had lost three lakh of rupees, he had managed to retain his kingdom.",
        "extract": "In two days a bill for three lakh of rupees came from the British jewellers. The Maharaja was happy that though he had lost three lakh of rupees, he had managed to retain his kingdom.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L79:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many tigers was the Maharaja able to kill within ten years?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L81:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L81:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened to the tiger population in the forests of Pratibandapuram?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L81:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja do one day?",
        "answer": "One day the Maharaja sent for the dewan.",
        "extract": "One day the Maharaja sent for the dewan.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L83:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did he ask the dewan?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the dewan's reaction?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja decide to do?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the dewan's response to the Maharaja's decision to get married?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja want?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the dewan suggest the Maharaja marry?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Maharaja's response to the dewan's suggestion?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja want the dewan to do first?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the dewan find?",
        "answer": "The dewan went home convinced that if the Maharaja did not find the tiger soon, the results could be catastrophic. He felt life returning to him only when he saw the tiger which had been brought from the People\u2019s Park in Madras and kept hidden in his house.",
        "extract": "The dewan went home convinced that if the Maharaja did not find the tiger soon, the results could be catastrophic. He felt life returning to him only when he saw the tiger which had been brought from the People\u2019s Park in Madras and kept hidden in his house.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L125:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many tigers did the Maharaja kill each time he visited his father-in-law?",
        "answer": "Maharaja Jung Jung Bahadur killed five or six tigers each time he visited his father-in-law. In this manner, ninety-nine tiger skins adorned the walls of the reception hall in the Pratibandapuram palace.",
        "extract": "Maharaja Jung Jung Bahadur killed five or six tigers each time he visited his father-in-law. In this manner, ninety-nine tiger skins adorned the walls of the reception hall in the Pratibandapuram palace.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L105:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many tiger skins adorned the walls of the reception hall in the Pratibandapuram palace?",
        "answer": "Maharaja Jung Jung Bahadur killed five or six tigers each time he visited his father-in-law. In this manner, ninety-nine tiger skins adorned the walls of the reception hall in the Pratibandapuram palace.",
        "extract": "Maharaja Jung Jung Bahadur killed five or six tigers each time he visited his father-in-law. In this manner, ninety-nine tiger skins adorned the walls of the reception hall in the Pratibandapuram palace.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L105:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did the Maharaja's anxiety reach a fever pitch?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L107:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was his one thought during the day and the same dream at night?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L107:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What had happened to the tiger farms?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L107:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the one thing needed?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s anxiety reached a fever pitch when there remained just one tiger to achieve his tally of a hundred. He had this one thought during the day and the same dream at night. By this time the tiger farms had run dry even in his father-in-law\u2019s kingdom. It became impossible to locate tigers anywhere. Yet only one more was needed. If he could kill just that one single beast, the Maharaja would have no fears left. He could give up tiger hunting altogether.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L107:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the late chief astrologer say?",
        "answer": "But he had to be extremely careful with that last tiger. What had the late chief astrologer said? \u201cEven after killing ninety-nine tigers the Maharaja should beware of the hundredth...\u2019\u2019 True enough. The tiger was a savage beast after all. One had to be wary of it. But where was that hundredth tiger to be found? It seemed easier to find tiger\u2019s milk than a live tiger.",
        "extract": "But he had to be extremely careful with that last tiger. What had the late chief astrologer said? \u201cEven after killing ninety-nine tigers the Maharaja should beware of the hundredth...\u2019\u2019 True enough. The tiger was a savage beast after all. One had to be wary of it. But where was that hundredth tiger to be found? It seemed easier to find tiger\u2019s milk than a live tiger.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L109:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the hundredth tiger like?",
        "answer": "\u201cBut you must be very careful with the hundredth tiger.\u201d",
        "extract": "\u201cBut you must be very careful with the hundredth tiger.\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L49:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What seemed easier to find than a live tiger?",
        "answer": "But he had to be extremely careful with that last tiger. What had the late chief astrologer said? \u201cEven after killing ninety-nine tigers the Maharaja should beware of the hundredth...\u2019\u2019 True enough. The tiger was a savage beast after all. One had to be wary of it. But where was that hundredth tiger to be found? It seemed easier to find tiger\u2019s milk than a live tiger.",
        "extract": "But he had to be extremely careful with that last tiger. What had the late chief astrologer said? \u201cEven after killing ninety-nine tigers the Maharaja should beware of the hundredth...\u2019\u2019 True enough. The tiger was a savage beast after all. One had to be wary of it. But where was that hundredth tiger to be found? It seemed easier to find tiger\u2019s milk than a live tiger.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L109:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happy news dispelled the Maharaja's gloom?",
        "answer": "Thus the Maharaja was sunk in gloom. But soon came the happy news which dispelled that gloom. In his own state sheep began to disappear frequently from a hillside village.",
        "extract": "Thus the Maharaja was sunk in gloom. But soon came the happy news which dispelled that gloom. In his own state sheep began to disappear frequently from a hillside village.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L111:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was first ascertained?",
        "answer": "It was first ascertained that this was not the work of Khader Mian Saheb or Virasami Naicker, both famed for their ability to swallow sheep whole. Surely, a tiger was at work. The villagers ran to inform the Maharaja. The Maharaja announced a three-year exemption from all taxes for that village and set out on the hunt at once.",
        "extract": "It was first ascertained that this was not the work of Khader Mian Saheb or Virasami Naicker, both famed for their ability to swallow sheep whole. Surely, a tiger was at work. The villagers ran to inform the Maharaja. The Maharaja announced a three-year exemption from all taxes for that village and set out on the hunt at once.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L113:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the villagers do?",
        "answer": "\u201cWhat do you say now?\u201d he demanded.",
        "extract": "\u201cWhat do you say now?\u201d he demanded.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L43:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja announce?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Was the tiger easily found?",
        "answer": "The tiger was not easily found. It seemed as if it had wantonly hid itself in order to flout the Maharaja\u2019s will.",
        "extract": "The tiger was not easily found. It seemed as if it had wantonly hid itself in order to flout the Maharaja\u2019s will.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L115:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja refuse to do?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened as the days passed?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja was equally determined. He refused to leave the forest until the tiger was found. As the days passed, the Maharaja\u2019s fury and obstinacy mounted alarmingly. Many officers lost their jobs.",
        "extract": "The Maharaja was equally determined. He refused to leave the forest until the tiger was found. As the days passed, the Maharaja\u2019s fury and obstinacy mounted alarmingly. Many officers lost their jobs.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L117:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja order the dewan to do one day?",
        "answer": "One day the Maharaja sent for the dewan.",
        "extract": "One day the Maharaja sent for the dewan.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L83:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the dewan's response?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the king say to the dewan?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the dewan do?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where had the tiger been brought from?",
        "answer": "The dewan went home convinced that if the Maharaja did not find the tiger soon, the results could be catastrophic. He felt life returning to him only when he saw the tiger which had been brought from the People\u2019s Park in Madras and kept hidden in his house.",
        "extract": "The dewan went home convinced that if the Maharaja did not find the tiger soon, the results could be catastrophic. He felt life returning to him only when he saw the tiger which had been brought from the People\u2019s Park in Madras and kept hidden in his house.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L125:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the dewan and his aged wife do at midnight?",
        "answer": "At midnight when the town slept in peace, the dewan and his aged wife dragged the tiger to the car and shoved it into the seat. The dewan himself drove the car straight to the forest where the Maharaja was hunting. When they reached the forest the tiger launched its satyagraha and refused to get out of the car. The dewan was thoroughly exhausted in his efforts to haul the beast out of the car and push it down to the ground.",
        "extract": "At midnight when the town slept in peace, the dewan and his aged wife dragged the tiger to the car and shoved it into the seat. The dewan himself drove the car straight to the forest where the Maharaja was hunting. When they reached the forest the tiger launched its satyagraha and refused to get out of the car. The dewan was thoroughly exhausted in his efforts to haul the beast out of the car and push it down to the ground.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L127:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the tiger do when they reached the forest?",
        "answer": "At midnight when the town slept in peace, the dewan and his aged wife dragged the tiger to the car and shoved it into the seat. The dewan himself drove the car straight to the forest where the Maharaja was hunting. When they reached the forest the tiger launched its satyagraha and refused to get out of the car. The dewan was thoroughly exhausted in his efforts to haul the beast out of the car and push it down to the ground.",
        "extract": "At midnight when the town slept in peace, the dewan and his aged wife dragged the tiger to the car and shoved it into the seat. The dewan himself drove the car straight to the forest where the Maharaja was hunting. When they reached the forest the tiger launched its satyagraha and refused to get out of the car. The dewan was thoroughly exhausted in his efforts to haul the beast out of the car and push it down to the ground.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L127:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened on the following day?",
        "answer": "On the following day, the same old tiger wandered into the Maharaja\u2019s presence and stood as if in humble supplication, \u201cMaster, what do you command of me?\u2019\u2019 It was with boundless joy that the Maharaja took careful aim at the beast. The tiger fell in a crumpled heap.",
        "extract": "On the following day, the same old tiger wandered into the Maharaja\u2019s presence and stood as if in humble supplication, \u201cMaster, what do you command of me?\u2019\u2019 It was with boundless joy that the Maharaja took careful aim at the beast. The tiger fell in a crumpled heap.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L129:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja do?",
        "answer": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "extract": "The British officer\u2019s secretary sent word to the Maharaja through the dewan that the durai himself did not have to kill the tiger. The Maharaja could do the actual killing. What was important to the durai was a photograph of himself holding the gun and standing over the tiger\u2019s carcass. But the Maharaja would not agree even to this proposal. If he relented now, what would he do if other British officers turned up for tiger hunts?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L71:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Maharaja say?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the hunters do after the Maharaja left?",
        "answer": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "extract": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L133:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did they realize?",
        "answer": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "extract": "\u201cThe child will grow up to become the warrior of warriors, hero of heroes, champion of champions. But...\u2019\u2019 they bit their lips and swallowed hard. When compelled to continue, the astrologers came out with it. \u201cThis is a secret which should not be revealed at all. And yet we are forced to speak out. The child born under this star will one day have to meet its death.\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L9:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What had happened to the tiger?",
        "answer": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "extract": "The manner of his death is a matter of extraordinary interest. It can be revealed only at the end of the tale. The most fantastic aspect of his demise was that as soon as he was born, astrologers had foretold that one day the Tiger King would actually have to die.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L7:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the hunters decide?",
        "answer": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "extract": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L133:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did one of the hunters do?",
        "answer": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "extract": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L133:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened to the dead tiger?",
        "answer": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "extract": "Right at the start, it is imperative to disclose a matter of vital importance about the Tiger King. Everyone who reads of him will experience the natural desire to meet a man of his indomitable courage face-to-face. But there is no chance of its fulfilment. As Bharata said to Rama about Dasaratha, the Tiger King has reached that final abode of all living creatures. In other words, the Tiger King is dead.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L5:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was celebrated a few days later?",
        "answer": "A few days later the Maharaja\u2019s son\u2019s third birthday was celebrated. Until then the Maharaja had given his entire mind over to tiger hunting. He had had no time to spare for the crown prince.",
        "extract": "A few days later the Maharaja\u2019s son\u2019s third birthday was celebrated. Until then the Maharaja had given his entire mind over to tiger hunting. He had had no time to spare for the crown prince.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L137:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What had the Maharaja given his entire mind over to until then?",
        "answer": "A few days later the Maharaja\u2019s son\u2019s third birthday was celebrated. Until then the Maharaja had given his entire mind over to tiger hunting. He had had no time to spare for the crown prince.",
        "extract": "A few days later the Maharaja\u2019s son\u2019s third birthday was celebrated. Until then the Maharaja had given his entire mind over to tiger hunting. He had had no time to spare for the crown prince.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L137:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the king wish to give his son?",
        "answer": "But now the king turned his attention to the child. He wished to give him some special gift on his birthday. He went to the shopping centre in Pratibandapuram and searched every shop, but couldn\u2019t find anything suitable. Finally he spotted a wooden tiger in a toyshop and decided it was the perfect gift.",
        "extract": "But now the king turned his attention to the child. He wished to give him some special gift on his birthday. He went to the shopping centre in Pratibandapuram and searched every shop, but couldn\u2019t find anything suitable. Finally he spotted a wooden tiger in a toyshop and decided it was the perfect gift.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L139:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did he go to find a gift?",
        "answer": "But now the king turned his attention to the child. He wished to give him some special gift on his birthday. He went to the shopping centre in Pratibandapuram and searched every shop, but couldn\u2019t find anything suitable. Finally he spotted a wooden tiger in a toyshop and decided it was the perfect gift.",
        "extract": "But now the king turned his attention to the child. He wished to give him some special gift on his birthday. He went to the shopping centre in Pratibandapuram and searched every shop, but couldn\u2019t find anything suitable. Finally he spotted a wooden tiger in a toyshop and decided it was the perfect gift.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L139:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did he finally spot?",
        "answer": "But now the king turned his attention to the child. He wished to give him some special gift on his birthday. He went to the shopping centre in Pratibandapuram and searched every shop, but couldn\u2019t find anything suitable. Finally he spotted a wooden tiger in a toyshop and decided it was the perfect gift.",
        "extract": "But now the king turned his attention to the child. He wished to give him some special gift on his birthday. He went to the shopping centre in Pratibandapuram and searched every shop, but couldn\u2019t find anything suitable. Finally he spotted a wooden tiger in a toyshop and decided it was the perfect gift.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L139:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much did the wooden tiger cost?",
        "answer": "The wooden tiger cost only two annas and a quarter. But the shopkeeper knew that if he quoted such a low price to the Maharaja, he would be punished under the rules of the Emergency. So, he said, \u201cYour Majesty, this is an extremely rare example of craftsmanship. A bargain at three hundred rupees!\u201d",
        "extract": "The wooden tiger cost only two annas and a quarter. But the shopkeeper knew that if he quoted such a low price to the Maharaja, he would be punished under the rules of the Emergency. So, he said, \u201cYour Majesty, this is an extremely rare example of craftsmanship. A bargain at three hundred rupees!\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L141:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the shopkeeper say the price was?",
        "answer": "The wooden tiger cost only two annas and a quarter. But the shopkeeper knew that if he quoted such a low price to the Maharaja, he would be punished under the rules of the Emergency. So, he said, \u201cYour Majesty, this is an extremely rare example of craftsmanship. A bargain at three hundred rupees!\u201d",
        "extract": "The wooden tiger cost only two annas and a quarter. But the shopkeeper knew that if he quoted such a low price to the Maharaja, he would be punished under the rules of the Emergency. So, he said, \u201cYour Majesty, this is an extremely rare example of craftsmanship. A bargain at three hundred rupees!\u201d",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L141:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the king say to the shopkeeper?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the father and son do on that day?",
        "answer": "On that day father and son played with that tiny little wooden tiger. It had been carved by an unskilled carpenter. Its surface was rough; tiny slivers of wood stood up like quills all over it. One of those slivers pierced the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. He pulled it out with his left hand and continued to play with the prince.",
        "extract": "On that day father and son played with that tiny little wooden tiger. It had been carved by an unskilled carpenter. Its surface was rough; tiny slivers of wood stood up like quills all over it. One of those slivers pierced the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. He pulled it out with his left hand and continued to play with the prince.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L145:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who had the wooden tiger been carved by?",
        "answer": "On that day father and son played with that tiny little wooden tiger. It had been carved by an unskilled carpenter. Its surface was rough; tiny slivers of wood stood up like quills all over it. One of those slivers pierced the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. He pulled it out with his left hand and continued to play with the prince.",
        "extract": "On that day father and son played with that tiny little wooden tiger. It had been carved by an unskilled carpenter. Its surface was rough; tiny slivers of wood stood up like quills all over it. One of those slivers pierced the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. He pulled it out with his left hand and continued to play with the prince.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L145:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was its surface like?",
        "answer": "On that day father and son played with that tiny little wooden tiger. It had been carved by an unskilled carpenter. Its surface was rough; tiny slivers of wood stood up like quills all over it. One of those slivers pierced the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. He pulled it out with his left hand and continued to play with the prince.",
        "extract": "On that day father and son played with that tiny little wooden tiger. It had been carved by an unskilled carpenter. Its surface was rough; tiny slivers of wood stood up like quills all over it. One of those slivers pierced the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. He pulled it out with his left hand and continued to play with the prince.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L145:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened to the Maharaja?",
        "answer": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "THE Maharaja of Pratibandapuram is the hero of this story. He may be identified as His Highness Jamedar-General, Khiledar-Major, Sata Vyaghra Samhari, Maharajadhiraja Visva Bhuvana Samrat, Sir Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, M.A.D., A.C.T.C., or C.R.C.K. But this name is often shortened to the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L1:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did he do with the sliver?",
        "answer": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "extract": "Crown prince Jung Jung Bahadur grew taller and stronger day by day. No other miracle marked his childhood days apart from the event already described. The boy drank the milk of an English cow, was brought up by an English nanny, tutored in English by an Englishman, saw nothing but English films \u2014 exactly as the crown princes of all the other Indian states did. When he came of age at twenty, the State, which had been with the Court of Wards until then, came into his hands.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L35:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened the next day?",
        "answer": "The next day, infection flared in the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. In four days, it developed into a suppurating sore which spread all over the arm.",
        "extract": "The next day, infection flared in the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. In four days, it developed into a suppurating sore which spread all over the arm.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L147:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the infection develop into in four days?",
        "answer": "The next day, infection flared in the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. In four days, it developed into a suppurating sore which spread all over the arm.",
        "extract": "The next day, infection flared in the Maharaja\u2019s right hand. In four days, it developed into a suppurating sore which spread all over the arm.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L147:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was brought in from Madras?",
        "answer": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "extract": "The Maharaja\u2019s tiger hunts continued to be highly successful. Within ten years he was able to kill seventy tigers. And then, an unforeseen hurdle brought his mission to a standstill. The tiger population became extinct in the forests of Pratibandapuram. Who knows whether the tigers practised birth control or committed harakiri? Or simply ran away from the State because they desired to be shot by British hands alone?",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L81:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did they decide to do?",
        "answer": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "extract": "After the Maharaja left, the hunters went to take a closer look at the tiger. The tiger looked back at them rolling its eyes in bafflement. The men realised that the tiger was not dead; the bullet had missed it. It had fainted from the shock of the bullet whizzing past. The hunters wondered what they should do. They decided that the Maharaja must not come to know that he had missed his target. If he did, they could lose their jobs. One of the hunters took aim from a distance of one foot and shot the tiger. This time he killed it without missing his mark.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L133:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the three surgeons announce after the operation?",
        "answer": "Three famous surgeons were brought in from Madras. After holding a consultation they decided to operate. The operation took place.",
        "extract": "Three famous surgeons were brought in from Madras. After holding a consultation they decided to operate. The operation took place.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L149:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what manner did the hundredth tiger take its final revenge upon the Tiger King?",
        "answer": "In this manner the hundredth tiger took its final revenge upon the Tiger King.",
        "extract": "In this manner the hundredth tiger took its final revenge upon the Tiger King.",
        "citation": "The Tiger King.md#L153:1"
    }
]